Guide to the Jerome T. Barrett Collection, 1913-2010 LAC0007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- The Friends of Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service History Archive, 1919-2010; Record Group 1; 68.5 Linear Feet
  - General/Institutional, 1946-2010; Record Group 1 Series 2; 23.5 Linear Feet
    - Bulletins, Press Clippings and News Releases, 1947-2004; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 11
      - Office of Information and Public Affairs-Clippings, 1985; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 11 (Box 269, Folder 3)
      - Office of Information and Public Affairs-Clippings, 1986; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 11 (Box 269, Folder 4)
      - Office of Information and Public Affairs-Clippings, 1986; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 11 (Box 269, Folder 5)
    - Industry Files, 1967-1997; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12
      - Shipbuilding Industry, 1967-1971; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 263, Folder 1)
      - United Auto Workers Resource Manual, 1967; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 263, Folder 2)
      - Teamster-Trucker Negotiations, 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 263, Folder 3)
      - Impact of Longhorn Strikes on National Economy, 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 263, Folder 4)
      - UAW-GM [1 of 2], 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 263, Folder 5)
      - UAW-GM [2 of 2], 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 1)
      - Postal Negotiation History by DOL (1), 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 2)
      - Postal Negotiation History by DOL (2), 1970; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 3)
      - Longhouse East Coast-Part 1, 1971; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 4)
      - Longhouse East Coast-Part 2, 1971; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 5)
      - Longhouse East Coast-Part 3, 1971; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 264, Folder 6)
      - Maritime Industry [1 of 2], 1972; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 265, Folder 1)
      - Maritime Industry [2 of 2], 1972; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 265, Folder 2)
      - Health Care Industry, 1974; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 265, Folder 3)
      - Oglaloi Sioux Primary & General Elections-Photo Album, 1975-1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 1)
      - Oglaloi Sioux Primary & General Elections-General Report, 1975-1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 2)
      - URW Strike, Auto Mechanics [1 of 2], 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 3)
      - URW Strike, Auto Mechanics [2 of 2], 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 4)
      - Miscellanous (1), 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 5)
      - Miscellanous (2), 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 266, Folder 6)
      - United Parcel Service & Teamsters Negotiations, 1974; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 1)
      - Baltimore Teachers, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 2)
      - California Cannery, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 3)
      - Construction Contractors Council, Inc., 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 4)
      - Florida Power and Light, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 5)
      - Clothing Workers, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 6)
      - Rubber, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 7)
      - Washington Post, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 8)
      - United Airlines, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 9)
      - Alaska Pipeline, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 267, Folder 10)
      - U.S. Post Office, 1975; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 1)
      - Cannery Workers Strike [1 of 2], July, 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 2)
      - Cannery Workers Strike [2 of 2], July, 1976; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 3)
      - Bridgestone-Firestone Strike, 1994; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 4)
      - Baseball Negotiations, 1994; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 5)
      - Wheeling-Pittsburgh Steel Strike [1 of 3], 1996; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 6)
      - Wheeling-Pittsburgh Steel Strike [2 of 3], 1997; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 6)
      - Wheeling-Pittsburgh Steel Strike [3 of 3], 1997; Record Group 1 Series 2 Subseries 12 (Box 268, Folder 7)
  - Mediator Training and Orientation, 1953-2002; Record Group 1 Series 3; 8 Linear Feet
    - Mediator Training, 1962-1998; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1; 4.5 Linear Feet
      This subseries contains materials dating from 1962-1998 relating to the FMCS' National Seminars, Regional Conferences, and other sites of training for its mediators. Included is correspondence between organizers of the events and FMCS mediators, seminar/conference agendas and logistics, workshop information, speech transcripts, biographies of people related to the field of labor dispute mediation, and press coverage of the different events.
      This subseries is arranged chronologically by the date of the seminar/conference/etc. for which the material was produced.
      - 1963 National Seminar - General, 1962-1963; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - 1964 National Seminar - Correspondence, 1963-1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - 1964 National Seminar - General [1/2], 1963-1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - 1964 National Seminar - General [2/2], 1963-1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Workshop: "The Building and Construction Industry", 1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Workshop: "Job Evaluation", 1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Workshop: "Joint Study Committees", 1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Workshop: "Work Force Reduction", 1964; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - 1965 National Seminar - General [1/2], 1964-1965; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - 1965 National Seminar - General [2/2], 1964-1965; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Workshop: "Operational and Occupational Changes: The Impact on the Bargaining Unit", 1965; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Workshop: "The Remaining Work Force", 1965; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - 1966 National Seminar - General, 1965-1966; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - 1966 Regional Conferences - General, 1966-1968; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - 1967 National Seminar - Correspondence, 1966-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - 1967 National Seminar - Genmeral [1/2], 1966-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - 1967 National Seminar - General [2/2], 1966-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Biographies, 1962-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Press Coverage, 1966-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - "Seminar Follies", 1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Speeches, 1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - 1967 Regional Conferences - General, 1966-1967; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - 1968 National Seminar - General, 1967-1968; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - 1969 Regional Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - 1969 National Seminar - General [1/3], 1968-1969; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - 1969 National Seminar - General [2/3], 1968-1969; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - 1969 National Seminar - General [3/3], 1968-1969; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - 1970 National Seminar - General [1/2], 1969-1970; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - 1970 National Seminar - General [2/2], 1969-1970; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - 1971 National Seminar - General, 1970-1971; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - 1971 Regional Director Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - 1971 Regional Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - 1972 National Seminar - General [1/2], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - 1972 National Seminar - General [2/2], 1971-1972; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Biographies, 1971; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Publicity, 1972; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Speeches, 1972; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - 1973 National Seminar - Correspondence, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - 1973 National Seminar - General [1/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - 1973 National Seminar - General [2/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - 1973 National Seminar - General [3/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Workshops - General, 1973; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Workshop: "Productivity Bargaining - Aspects for Mediator Consideration" [1/2], 1973; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Workshop: "Productivity Bargaining - Aspects for Mediator Consideration" [2/2], 1973; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - 1974 Executive Seminar - Correspondence, 1971-1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - 1974 Regional Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - 1975 National Seminar - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Speeches, 1975; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - 1977 National Seminar - Correspondence, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Workshops - General, 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - 1977 Regional Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - 1978 Regional Conferences - Workshops: General [1/2], 1977-1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - 1978 Regional Conferences - Workshops: General [2/2], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - Workshop: "Health Care", 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Workshop: "Mediation in the Federal Sector", 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - 1979 National Seminar - General [1/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - 1979 National Seminar - General [2/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - 1979 National Seminar - General [3/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - Workshop and Mediator Training Planning, 1979-1982; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - 1985 National Seminar - General, 1984-1985; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - 1987 National Seminar - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - 1987 District Conferences - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - 1989 National Seminar - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Effective Briefing and Instructional Techniques Training, 1989; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Western Region Training Conference - General, 1990; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - 1995 Professional Development Seminar - General [1/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - 1995 Professional Development Seminar - General [2/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - 1995 Professional Development Seminar - General [3/3], Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Workshop: "Federal Sector Partnerships", 1995; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - 1996 Regional Training Seminar - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - 1998 Professional Development Seminar - General, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Mediator Orientaion, 1953-2002; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2; 2 Linear Feet
      This subseries contains materials produced by the FMCS in the process of recruiting, interviewing, hiring and training new mediators. The materials date from 1953-2002. Included are lists of new mediator classes, mediator recruitment and interviewing procedures, mediator orientation materials, and other related materials.
      - FMCS Employment Opportunity Pamphlets, 1953-1963; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Mediator Job Descriptions, 1957-1972; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Mediator Recruitment, 1963-1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Orientation Notes, 1964 March 30 - April 10; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Preventive Mediation and Related Material, 1964 March-April; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - 1964 Mediator Class, 1964 October; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - 1965 Mediator Class, 1965 May; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Mediator Interviews / Travel and Lodging Expenses, 1971-1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - New Mediator Evaluation Report, 1971-1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Mediator Interview Process, 1972; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Mediator-Intern Training Program, 1972-1981; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Mediator Orientaion, 1973 August 27-31; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Mediator Training in the Field, 1973-1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 13)
      - Mediator Recruitment Task Force [1/3], 1973-1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 14)
      - Mediator Recruitment Task Force [2/3], 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 37, Folder 15)
      - Mediator Recruitment Task Force [3/3], 1974-1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Mediator Interviews [1/4], 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Mediator Interviews [2/4], 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Mediator Interviews [3/4], 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Mediator Interviews [4/4], 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Mediator Orientation, 1974; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Recruiting Women, 1974 October 29-30; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Assessment of New Mediator-Intern Class, 1974-1975; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Mediator Evaluation and Training, 1974-1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Mediator Orientation, 1975-1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Mediator-Intern Orientation, 1975-1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Intern Evaluation Program, 1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Mediator Orientation, 1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Mediator Orientation [1/2], 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Mediator Orientation [2/2], 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Mediator Orientation Planning, 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - New Mediator Evaluation, 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Mediator Professional Development Survey [1/3], 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Mediator Professional Development Survey [2/3], 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - Mediator Professional Development Survey [3/3], 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Para-Mediators, 1978; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Cornell University Fellowship, 1979; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Mediator Selection Process, 1979-1980; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - Mediator-Intern Selection Process, 1979-1981; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - Mediator Orientation, 1980; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - Mediator Recruitment Evaluation, 1985; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - National Office Mediator Orientation [1/5], 1988 December 4-9; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - National Office Mediator Orientation [2/5], 1988 December 4-9; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - National Office Mediator Orientation [3/5], 1988 December 4-9; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - National Office Mediator Orientation [4/5], 1988 December 4-9; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - National Office Mediator Orientation [5/5], 1988 December 4-9; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - 2001 Mediator Class, 2002; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 2 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Handbooks and Manuals, 1973-1992; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3; 1.5 Linear Feet
      This subseries is arranged chronologically by the date of the materials in each handbook/manual.
      Note: Chronology re-starts with Box 27, Folder 3. These materials were added after initial processing.
      This subseries contains FMCS mediator handbooks and manuals dating from 1973-1992. Topics covered by the materials include the organization of the FMCS, mediation procedures, budget information, and FMCS services.
      - Policy Directives Handbook [1/2], 1973-1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 25, Folder 1)
        Contains handbook sections labelled "Organization and Administration," "Mediation," and "Arbitration."
      - Policy Directives Handbook [2/2], 1973-1976; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 25, Folder 2)
        Contains handbook sections labelled "Personnel," "Budget & Finance," "Services and Supply," "Case Control Records & Procedures," and "Technical Services."
      - Directives Manual Volume 1, 1982; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 25, Folder 3)
        Volume 1 of 2.
      - Directives Manual Volume 2, 1982; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 26, Folder 1)
        Volume 2 of 2.
      - Mediator Case Administration Manual 1, 1982-1987; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Mediator Case Administration Manual 2, 1982-1987; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Mediator Case Administration Manual 3, 1982-1988; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Mediator Case Administration Manual 4, 1982-1982; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Revised Mediator Case Administration Manual, 1992; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Labor-Management Relations Resource Manual [1/2], 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Labor-Management Relations Resource Manual [2/2], 1977; Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Civil Service Reform Act of 1978 Training Manual, Record Group 1 Series 3 Subseries 3 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Alternative Dispute Resolution Books, 1989-1996 (Box 291)
        This box contains books about alternative dispute resolution.
  - Preventive Mediation, 1952-2007; Record Group 1 Series 4; 11 Linear Feet
    - Relationship by Objectives and Partners in Change, 1974-1995; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1; 4 Linear Feet
      Note: The chronology restarts with Box 55 Folder 8, as these materials were added after initial processing.
      This subseries contains materials related to the FMCS' Relationship by Objectives and Partners in Change Programs dating from 1974-1995. The materials range widely in scope and purpose. Included are reports on various RBO/PIC programs, manuals for RBO/PIC instructors and participants, RBO/PIC workshop information, articles and papers relating to RBO and PIC, and detailed information on the Food Safety Inspection Service vs. National Joint Council of Food Inspection Locals Federal Labor Relations Authority RBO Case, including a transcript of the proceedings.
      - RBO - Organizational Development [1/3], 1974-1981; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      - RBO - Organizational Development [2/3], 1974-1981; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 48, Folder 2)
      - RBO - Organizational Development [3/3], 1974-1981; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous RBO Material, 1974-1988; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Report on Georgia-Pacific Company Pilot Program [1/3], 1975; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Report on Georgia-Pacific Company Pilot Program [2/3], 1975; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Report on Georgia-Pacific Company Pilot Program [3/3], 1975; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Labor-Management RBO Resource Manual, 1975 November; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - "Causes of Industrial Organization Re-Revisited: The Case for RBO", 1976; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 4)
        Paper prepared by the Division of Research, Planning and Development, Office of Technical Services, FMCS for the "New Dimensions in Collective Bargaining" Conference.
      - RBO Evaluation, 1977-1978; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - RBO Programs by Region [1/2], 1977-1982; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - RBO Programs by Region [2/2], 1977-1982; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - RBO Informational Booklet, 1978; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - RBO Master's Thesis [1/4], 1980s; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - RBO Master's Thesis [2/4], 1980s; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - RBO Master's Thesis [3/4], 1980s; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - RBO Master's Thesis [4/4], 1980s; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - The Federal Service Labor-Management Relations Statute, 1980 January; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - RBO Reports and Studies, 1980-1981; Record Group 1 Series 4 Subseries 1 (Box 51, Folder 2)